<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineers Without Borders</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Engineers Without Borders</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ewbscu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"Student engineers give Nyange tile-making enterprise a big lift"</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/tile-press/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/tile-press/</guid><description>https://faithinactioninternational.org/student-engineers-give-nyange-tile-making-enterprise-a-big-lift/</description></item><item><title>10 Takeaways from Traveling to Rwanda</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/10-takeaways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/10-takeaways/</guid><description>Uche Agwu ‘18 recounts on what he learned during his time in Rwanda with the club.
https://www.scu.edu/engineering/stories/traveling-to-rwanda-top-10-lessons-i-learned.html</description></item><item><title>2018: Days 1-2</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-1-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-1-2/</guid><description>Hi all,
Muraho from Kigali! It’s the end of our second full day here in Rwanda, and we couldn’t be more grateful for how everything has gone. This is our first update email, and we will continue to send these emails out every couple of days. If you would like to be removed from the email list, please let me know! Also, for those in communication and media, please be sure to check any articles with us for accuracy and tone before publishing.</description></item><item><title>2018: Days 3-4</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-3-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-3-4/</guid><description>Hello from Nyange! Days 3 &amp;amp; 4
On Saturday we participated in Umuganda day (a nationwide day of community service held in every district every last Saturday of the month) at a school building site in the capital of Kigali. The EWB group packed onto the bus with the Food and Agribusiness Institute, the other Santa Clara Group that is in Rwanda at the same time as us. Together, our groups headed a short 10 minutes down the road to a school where hundreds of people had already begun swinging hoes and pick axes.</description></item><item><title>2018: Days 5-6</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-5-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-5-6/</guid><description>Hello from Nyange!
Muraho! (Hello!) The past two days have been amazing! We left Muhunga around 7:30 am to head to Nyange on both days. To respect the co-op members’ time and need to still work their crops and make food, we always plan to leave the community by 1 pm. For these two days, our team’s agenda included cooperative member interviews and cart assembly and testing on the local terrain.</description></item><item><title>2018: Days 7-8</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-7-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/days-7-8/</guid><description>What a productive couple of days we have had in the community. The first thing we want to do is send out the hugest thanks and kudos to the students and faculty from the Food and Agricultural Institute (FAI). They joined us in Nyange for both days 6 and 7. As we have mentioned in past communications, our community needed to widen their footpath to accommodate the electric cart.
When we arrived on day 4 to reconnect with the cooperative, we walked the new trail.</description></item><item><title>2018: PreTrip Work (Days -3 - 0)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/pretrip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/pretrip/</guid><description>The three days before the trip (August 18-21) were dedicated to the final adjustments on the cart, last minute trip logistics, and making sure that everything was packed and ready to go. Lauren, Isabella, and Sydney disassembled and reassembled the cart, taking careful note of what materials were used so that they could create an operational manual that will be translated into Kinyarwanda for the community to use. Teal, David, and Jon worked on finalizing the electrical wiring between the solar panel and the battery box.</description></item><item><title>2018: Quality Control Testing</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/qc1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/qc1/</guid><description>After designing the cart during the school year and the long hours put in during the evenings after work we were finally able to get our electric wagon on the trail to test it. Overall it went very well! The cart trekked up hill very easily, it was actually harder to go down hill! We learned that the front wheels need some adjustments to endure the loads. We made a video!</description></item><item><title>2018: Quality Control Testing 2</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/qc2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2018/qc2/</guid><description>After the failure of the front castor wheels in the last testing, we replaced the wheels with a much stronger brand of wheel. The new wheels are welded in two spots separated by a distance so that they can resist a moment caused by potential side loading. The QC2 tests these new castors, and we experiment with front/rear wheel drive. We ultimately decided to keep the rear wheel drive because otherwise the transaxle would take the brunt of the forces.</description></item><item><title>2019: Days 1-2</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-1-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-1-2/</guid><description>Greetings from Kigali!
We arrived on Tuesday evening to a warm welcome from Father Innocent, who is our everything. He organizes transport, lodging, some meals, gives the best hugs, inspires us, and we would be lost without him.
On Wednesday morning, we got off to an early start and headed out into Kigali to pick up SIM cards, exchange cash, and print some technical drawings of the cart to take to the welder.</description></item><item><title>2019: Days 13-14</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-13-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-13-14/</guid><description>Hello all,
Our last two days in Rwanda were busy and bittersweet. On Monday, the team split up for the last time: Garrett, Ben, and Dr. Doyle headed out to community to use a pump (the correct pump this time) to drain the borehole and obtain a flow rate, while David, Megan, Dr. T, and Katie stayed at Centre Christus to run calculations for the water project and pick up everyone’s clothes from the market.</description></item><item><title>2019: Days 3-5</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-3-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-3-5/</guid><description>Muraho (hello) all,
On Friday, our fourth day in country, the water team started organizing the water information and doing some research in order to figure out what questions to ask the community and the sector engineer who has been helping them with their project.
Innocent, the welder, surprised the team on Thursday night by revealing that the cart had been welded, so the cart team set off to Safintra Friday morning to pick up the cart and bring it to Sunpreme, the machine shop where the wheel clamps and battery box were being fabricated.</description></item><item><title>2019: Days 6-8</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-6-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-6-8/</guid><description>Hello y&amp;rsquo;all,
The theme of Monday was hurry up and wait. We woke up early to seize the day, but were delayed after breakfast waiting to coordinate transportation and drivers for the two teams. Once that was settled, the water team went to research the available pumps and piping available here in Rwanda while the cart team headed off to find a soldering gun.
While things were going smoothly for the water team, the cart team popped a tire on their vehicle halfway through the ride.</description></item><item><title>2019: Days 9-12</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-9-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2019/day-9-12/</guid><description>Hi all,
Our last two days in community, Thursday and Friday, passed very quickly. On Thursday, both the cart team and the water team headed into the community.
The cart team started the day by monitoring the old cart and asking interview questions, including what the community has been using it for, and how frequently they’ve used it over the course of the past year. After the interviews, Garrett and David took the new cart up the street to a nearby “water bar,” where water is available for purchase.</description></item><item><title>2022: Day 0 - 1 (Aug 15 - 16)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-0-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-0-1/</guid><description>Muraho!
We are excited to announce that our 2022 travel team is in Rwanda after kicking off our travel from SFO on August 13th. The students traveling this year are Mia Gabriele, Aaron Juan, and Katie Ott and are accompanied by EWB alumni and 3x past traveler Jon Borst, and civil engineering lab manager Brent Woodcock.
(Pictured from left to right: John R, Jon, Katie, Brent, Aaron, Mia, and Fr. Innocent)</description></item><item><title>2022: Day 2 - 3 (Aug 17 - 18)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-2-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-2-3/</guid><description>Muraho!
Day 2 Our team has just finished day three of our trip to Rwanda. On our second day in Kigali, we woke up early for a light jog to the airport to pick up our lost luggage. The jog took us through the rolling Kigali hills and local neighborhoods. We were impressed by the spacious green landscape in the hill valleys preserved by the city of Kigali. After returning to Centre Christus for what the team has decided is “the best coffee ever made,” we crammed into the Green Machine for a trip to the MTM cellular store.</description></item><item><title>2022: Day 5 - 6 (Aug 19 - 20)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-5-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-5-6/</guid><description>Muraho!
Day 5 Another early day for the team. So thankful for the priests at Don Bosco who packed us an exquisite breakfast of coffee, bananas, ground nuts, watermelon, bread, and bananas for the road. Lots of coffee was regrettably shared with the floor as the bus clamored down the road to the community. Upon arrival, we were once again greeted by the smiling faces of the technical students in their hard hats and coverall suits ready to work.</description></item><item><title>2022: Day 7 - 8 (Aug 21 - 22)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-7-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/travel-updates/2022/day-7-8/</guid><description>Muraho!
Day 7 We started the morning a little later than usual to respect the community’s worship hours on Sunday. Aaron and Jon took the extra time to run through the misty Muhunga hills. After eating another Don Bosco breakfast, the team hit the road to the community and got to work.
The morning was filled by tedious tasks including wire extension, delicately pushing wire into protective conduit, and more water source recharge measurements.</description></item><item><title>Aaron Juan</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/aaron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/aaron/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Aaron Juan</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/aaron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/aaron/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Aaron Juan</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/aaron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/aaron/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Adarsh Tantry</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/adarsh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/adarsh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alex Winter</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/alex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/alex/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An article by Mohit Nalavadi '16 about his experiences in EWB</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/mohit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/mohit/</guid><description>https://www.scu.edu/engineering/stories/engineering-news-winter-2016/pass-the-wrench-please.html</description></item><item><title>Andrew Torrance</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/andrew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/andrew/</guid><description/></item><item><title>April 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-apr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-apr/</guid><description>With the shallow cased well installed by the community, we continue to move towards transporting this water to our community. We are developing a graphic usage timeline to ensure that the community understands the necessary work required to operate and maintain our proposed water transportation solutions. We will also soon be able to resubmit our alternatives analysis report once we receive the water quality testing data.</description></item><item><title>Ben Mahony</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/ben/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/ben/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ben Mahony</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/ben/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/ben/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ben Mahony</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/ben/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/ben/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Benjamin Mahoney</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/benjamin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/benjamin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Brooke Watson</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/brooke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/brooke/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Caroline Stephens</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/caroline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/caroline/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Casey Xuereb</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/casey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/casey/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/contact/</guid><description>If you have any advice for us, feel free to reach out! We are open to gaining mentors in the field!
Email: ewb@scu.edu
Facebook: ewbSantaClara
Instagram: @ewb.scu
Youtube: EWB Santa Clara</description></item><item><title>Darran Casey</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/darran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/darran/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Darran Casey</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/darran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/darran/</guid><description/></item><item><title>David Gilbert</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/david/</guid><description/></item><item><title>David Gilbert</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/david/</guid><description/></item><item><title>David Gilbert</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/david/</guid><description/></item><item><title>David Gilbert</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/david/</guid><description/></item><item><title>EWB-SCU Annual 5k for $5k Fundraiser</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/5k-for-5k/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/5k-for-5k/</guid><description>1. What is a Virtual 5K run?
A &amp;ldquo;Virtual 5K&amp;rdquo; is a full 5-kilometer race than can be run wherever a participant chooses. This allows participants from around the world to come together and support SCU-EWB&amp;rsquo;s Virtual 5K for $5K! All you have to do is register online and complete a 5K run (or walk) anywhere and anytime between February 26th and 27th, 2022. Register Here
2. How do I register?</description></item><item><title>February 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-feb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-feb/</guid><description>Worked on submitting a pump evaluation and recommendation to Eric Lunborg, which would allow us to send it to the CO-OP.</description></item><item><title>Garrett Nelson</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/garrett/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/garrett/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Garrett Nelson</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/garrett/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/garrett/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Isabella Morales</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/isabella/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/isabella/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jack Hartline</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jack/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jada Paddock</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/jada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/jada/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jaden Ngo</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/jaden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/jaden/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jaden Ngo</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jaden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jaden/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jake Taylor</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/jake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/jake/</guid><description/></item><item><title>January 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-jan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-jan/</guid><description>We started off the year by updating the alternatives analysis report in response to the feedback provided by EWB nationals, and continuing research into solar powered pumps. Simultaneously, some officers coordinated the performance of a hydrogeological survey in the area of our cooperative as well as water quality testing from the water sources that the community is in favor of using. Some students worked with Dr. T, Dr. Doyle and Dr.</description></item><item><title>Jj Galvin</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/jj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/jj/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jonatahn Borst</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/jonathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/jonathan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jonathan Borst</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/jonathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/jonathan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jordan Mosakowski</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jordan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/jordan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Josephine Semaan</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/josephine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/josephine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Josephine Semann</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/josephine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/josephine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Josh Seo</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/josh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/josh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Joshua Seo</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/joshua/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/joshua/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Josie Warren</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/josie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/josie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Justin Culpepper</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/justin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/justin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Justyn Li</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/justyn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/justyn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katie Neighbors</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/katie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/katie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katie Neighbors</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/katie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/katie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katie Neighbors</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/katie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/katie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katie Neighbors</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/katie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/katie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katie Ott</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/katie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/katie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Laura Doyle</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/advisors/lauradoyle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/advisors/lauradoyle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lauren Serfas</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/lauren/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/lauren/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lindsay McConville</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/lindsay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/lindsay/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lindsay McConville</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/lindsay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/lindsay/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lindsay McConville</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/lindsay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/lindsay/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Meg Ackerson</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/meg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2017/meg/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Megan Sauter</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/megan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2020/megan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Megan Sauter</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/megan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/megan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Megan Sautter</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/megan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/megan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mia Gabriele</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/mia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/mia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mia Gabriele</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/mia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/mia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mia Gabriele</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/mia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/mia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ministries</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/ministries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/ministries/</guid><description>Engineering Ministry The Engineering Ministry is geared towards understanding the needs of our partnered community, brainstorming ways to support them, and designing and implementing solutions. We do work that requires many people with all different levels of understanding of engineering concepts. We look to bring problem solvers, critical thinkers, and hard workers together to learn more about improving our global village through engineering solutions.
Education Ministry The Education Ministry is in charge of “bridging the gap” between the rest of the EWB team and our partner community in Rwanda by fostering communication and understanding between the two groups.</description></item><item><title>Mohit Nalavadi</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/mohit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/mohit/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Morgan Fleshren</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/morgan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2021/morgan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Morgan Fleshren</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/morgan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/morgan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Morgan Fleshren</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/morgan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/morgan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nyange Co-Op</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/our-partner-communities/nyange-co-op/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/our-partner-communities/nyange-co-op/</guid><description>Since 2014, EWB-SCU has partnered with a small tile making cooperative in Nyange, Rwanda.</description></item><item><title>Nyange Electric Wagon (2018)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-wagon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-wagon/</guid><description>With a narrow width and fold down sides, this modular electric wagon has been optimized to carry clay for our community allowing them to use their time more effectively.</description></item><item><title>Nyange Tile Press (2017)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-tile-press/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-tile-press/</guid><description>This custom tile press was designed to increase the quality and quantity of tiles made by our community, thereby allowing them to sell the tiles for more money.</description></item><item><title>Nyange Water Filtration (2019-2022)</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-water/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/nyange-water/</guid><description>We are working to provide a secure and sustainable drinking-water system that can filter for bacteria, parasites, turbidity, and nitrates, and control water distribution.</description></item><item><title>Partners</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/partners/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pranav Pradhan</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/pranav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/pranav/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rebecca Barney</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2014/rebecca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2014/rebecca/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Renae Romandia McCoy</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/renae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/renae/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Renae Romandia McCoy</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/renae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/renae/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ryan Sidley</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/ryan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2016/ryan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Safintra partnered with Engineers Without Borders</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/safintra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/club-updates/safintra/</guid><description>Safintra Rwanda Limited partners with SCU’s EWB to facilitate the transportation of water for home use in Nyange sector of Ngororero district, Western Province.
http://www.hope-mag.com/index.php?com=news&amp;amp;option=read&amp;amp;ca=7&amp;amp;a=4455</description></item><item><title>Sam Broyles</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/sam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/sam/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sam Broyles</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/sam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/sam/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shiyin Lim</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/shiyin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2019/shiyin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shiyin Lim</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/shiyin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2018/shiyin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simitrio Arellano</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/simitrio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2019/simitrio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simitrio Arellano</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/simitrio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/simitrio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Taryn Chisholm</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/taryn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2021/taryn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Taryn Chisholm</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/taryn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2022/taryn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Theo Schapp</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2013/theo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2013/theo/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tonya Nilsson</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/advisors/tonyanilson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/advisors/tonyanilson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uchechukwu Agwu</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/uchechukwu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/alumni/2018/uchechukwu/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Valley Verde</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/our-partner-communities/valley-verde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/our-partner-communities/valley-verde/</guid><description>In 2021, EWB-SCU started up a new partnership working on a local project with Valley Verde.</description></item><item><title>Valley Verde</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/valley-verde-seedlings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/projects/valley-verde-seedlings/</guid><description>We are aiming to design an efficient and cost effective irrigation system to water seedlings for the local non-profit organization, Valley Verde.</description></item><item><title>Victoria Sanchez-Monroy</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/victoria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/victoria/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Voluntourism</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/voluntourism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/voluntourism/</guid><description>Throughout our travels, EWB has attempted to educate ourselves and avoid some of the common pitfalls of harmful voluntourism. Below is a report that part of our 2019 travel team completed, detailing some of our own trial and error as well as outside research on how to support communities in developing nations while minimizing the harm that can occur with profit-centric voluntourism. Some common mistakes include white saviorism, false representation of culture, and exploitation of children.</description></item><item><title>What We Do</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/what-we-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/what-we-do/</guid><description>Our Story Since 2014, EWB-SCU has partnered with a small tile making cooperative in Nyange, Rwanda. Our CO-OP is comprised of subsistence farmers, who use the income gained from selling their tiles to send their children to school and feed their families&amp;ndash;adults typically eat only one meal per day, while children have only two. Currently, there are 13 members of the CO-OP who each spend an average of 3 days a week making tiles.</description></item><item><title>Zach Gotvald</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/zach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/officers/2020/zach/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>