<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project updates on Engineers Without Borders</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/</link><description>Recent content in Project updates on Engineers Without Borders</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>April 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-apr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-apr/</guid><description>With the shallow cased well installed by the community, we continue to move towards transporting this water to our community. We are developing a graphic usage timeline to ensure that the community understands the necessary work required to operate and maintain our proposed water transportation solutions. We will also soon be able to resubmit our alternatives analysis report once we receive the water quality testing data.</description></item><item><title>February 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-feb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-feb/</guid><description>Worked on submitting a pump evaluation and recommendation to Eric Lunborg, which would allow us to send it to the CO-OP.</description></item><item><title>January 2021 Update</title><link>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-jan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ewbscu.github.io/project-updates/2021-jan/</guid><description>We started off the year by updating the alternatives analysis report in response to the feedback provided by EWB nationals, and continuing research into solar powered pumps. Simultaneously, some officers coordinated the performance of a hydrogeological survey in the area of our cooperative as well as water quality testing from the water sources that the community is in favor of using. Some students worked with Dr. T, Dr. Doyle and Dr.</description></item></channel></rss>